Hays mss., 1900-1985 LMC 2671
Lilly Library
- Writings (Box 9)
  - Writings by Will Hays Jr. (Box 9)
    - Loose on the Wind draft, pp. 301-400 (Box 26)
    - Loose on the Wind draft, pp. 401-534 (Box 26)
    - Come Home with Me Now draft, pp. 1-100 (Box 26)
    - Come Home with Me Now draft, pp. 101-200 (Box 26)
    - Come Home with Me Now draft, pp. 201-300 (Box 26)
    - Come Home with Me Now draft, pp. 301-400 (Box 26)
    - Come Home with Me Now draft, pp. 401-518 (Box 26)
    - Come Home with Me Now"final copy," pp. 1-100 (Box 26)
    - Come Home with Me Now"final copy," pp. 101-200 (Box 26)
    - Come Home with Me Now"final copy," pp. 201-300 (Box 26)
    - Come Home with Me Now"final copy," pp. 301-400 (Box 26)
    - Come Home with Me Now"final copy," pp. 401-576 (Box 26)
    - Come Home with Me Now"absolute original of 1981," pp. 1-100 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"absolute original of 1981," pp. 101-200 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"absolute original of 1981," pp. 201-300 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"absolute original of 1981," pp. 301-400 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"absolute original of 1981," pp. 401-500 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"absolute original of 1981," pp. 501-576 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"1st copy of original," pp. 1-100 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"1st copy of original," pp. 101-200 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"1st copy of original," pp. 201-300 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"1st copy of original," pp. 301-400 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"1st copy of original," pp. 401-500 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"1st copy of original," pp. 501-600 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"1st copy of original," pp. 601-677 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"copy of 1981," pp. 1-100 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"copy of 1981," pp. 101-200 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"copy of 1981," pp. 201-300 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"copy of 1981," pp. 301-400 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"copy of 1981," pp. 401-500 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"copy of 1981," pp. 501-576 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"copy of 1981," (II), pp. 1-100 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"copy of 1981," (II), pp. 101-200 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"copy of 1981," (II), pp. 201-300 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"copy of 1981," (II), pp. 301-400 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"copy of 1981," (II), pp. 401-500 (Box 27)
    - Come Home with Me Now"copy of 1981," (II), pp. 501-576 (Box 27)
- Photographs (Box 13)
  - Frame 1, Will Hays with two uniformed men, autographed to Billie Hays (Box 13)
  - Frame 2, man with three children, including Billie Hays (Box 13)
  - Frame 3, Will Hays and son in cowboy costume (Box 13)
  - Frame 4, L. H. French on horse, autographed 1883, with inscription to Bill Hays, 1936 (Box 13)
  - Frame 5, autographed photograph of Bill Hart signed to Bill Hays, Jr. (Box 13)
  - Frame 6, Will Hays and man with Bill Hays on horse (Box 13)
  - Frame 7, Bill Hays with three men and dog (Box 13)
  - California Beach, early 1930s, (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Connery Pasadena, 1925 (Box 13)
  - Dogs and Horses (Box 13)
  - Movies and Parties (Box 13)
  - Portraits, including Will Hays, and autographed portraits of Jimmie Adams, Virginia de Corbin, Neal Burns, Ruth Clifford, Billy Dooley, Billie Dove, Jack Duffy, "Gad", Bill Hart, Bill Irving, Osa Johnson, Doris Kenyon, Tom Mix, Vera Steadman, Shirley Temple, Bobby Vernon, Paul Vincenti, and Loretta Young (Box 13)
  - Candid photographs, (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Album 1, California and Arizona; Europe,; Summer,; Estes Park, Colorado, 1908; 1909; 1910; 1911-1912 (Box 13)
  - Album 2, childhood photographs of Bill Hays (Box 13)
  - Album 3, photographs of Will Hays, undated (Box 13)
  - Album 4, Horses and Dogs (Box 20)
  - Will Hays (Box 22)
    Nearly all of the photographic portraits are autographed by the subjects.
  - Mary Astor (Box 22)
  - Viola Banky (Box 22)
  - Warner Baxter (Box 22)
  - Noah Beery (Box 22)
  - Monte Blue (Box 22)
  - Clara Bow (Box 22)
  - Mary Brian (Box 22)
  - Clive Brook (Box 22)
  - Eddie Cantor (Box 22)
  - Lon Chaney, Sr. (Box 22)
  - Syd Chaplin (Box 22)
  - Ronald Colman (Box 22)
  - Maria Corda (Box 22)
  - Dolores Costello (Box 22)
  - Bebe Daniels (Box 22)
  - Dorothy Devore (Box 22)
  - Billie Dove (Box 22)
  - Louise Fazenda (Box 22)
  - W. C. Fields (Box 22)
  - Lillian Gish (Box 22)
  - Lawrence Gray (Box 22)
  - Corinne Griffith (Box 22)
  - Raymond Griffith (Box 22)
  - Bill Hart (Box 22)
  - Raymond Hatton (Box 22)
  - Lloyd Hughes (Box 22)
  - Emil Jannings (Box 22)
  - Leatrice Joy (Box 22)
  - Alice Joyce (Box 22)
  - Buster Keaton (Box 22)
  - Donald Keith (Box 22)
  - Natalie Kingston (Box 22)
  - Lupino Lane (Box 22)
  - Harry Langdon (Box 22)
  - Count Felix von Luckner (Box 22)
  - Dorothy Mackaill (Box 22)
  - Tim McCoy (Box 22)
  - Victor McLaglen (Box 22)
  - Jack Mulhall (Box 22)
  - Charlie Murray (Box 22)
  - Molly O'Day (Box 22)
  - Mary Pickford (Box 22)
  - William Powell (Box 22)
  - Esther Ralston (Box 22)
  - Carroll Reece (Box 22)
  - Donald Reed (Box 22)
  - Will Rogers (Box 22)
  - Chic Sale (Box 22)
  - Malcolm Sebastian, a.k.a. "Big Boy" (Box 22)
  - Gloria Swanson (Box 22)
  - Constance Talmadge (Box 22)
  - Estelle Taylor (Box 22)
  - Virginia Valli (Box 22)
  - Alice White (Box 22)
  - Irene Rich (Box 25)
  - Adolph Zukor (Box 25)
  - Original scrapbook enclosure (Box 25)
- Chaney Digest (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #1: "Headline" –, 1890-1906 (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #2: Sullivan Union, (6 folders) (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #3: Indiana Politics –, 1914 (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #4: Council of Defense Minutes (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #6: The Chaney Digest of Scrap Books National Politics, February 1918-February 22, 1922; (3 folders) (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #7: The Chaney Digest of Scrap Books The Postmaster General, March 3, 1921-March 4, 1922; (3 folders) (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #9: Summary of Box 56, (1919-1921) (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #11: MPPDA events, 1919-1935 (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #13: MPPDA events, 1938-1945 (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #14: European Visit, 11/7 – 12/2/1936 (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #15: Articles, Write-ups, Interviews, etc. etc. (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #16: Wise Will Case, Sept 1, 1947 (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #17: Letter Files in Boxes, (4 folders) (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #18: Digest of Indianapolis Star, Dec 1, 1947, (4 folders) (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #19: Indianapolis News, July 2, 1948 (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #20: Murphy Memo, WHH copy, (3 folders) (Box 14)
  - Chaney Digest #20: Murphy Memo, WHH copy, continued, (13 folders) (Box 15)
  - Chaney Digest #20: Murphy Memo, RHM copy, (18 folders) (Box 15)
- Diaries (Box 16)
  - Diaries and, 1916; 1921 (Box 16)
  - Calendar, 7 March 1921 – 3 March 1922 (Box 16)
  - Diaries and, 1946; 1947 (Box 16)
  - Diary, 1948 (Box 16)
  - Diaries and, 1951; 1952 (Box 16)
  - Diaries and, 1953; 1954 (Box 16)
  - Diary of William H. Hays Jr., 1932 (Box 16)
- Genealogical Materials (Box 16)
  - Cain Family, research notes (Box 16)
  - Cain Family, Ancestral Notes (Box 16)
  - Cain Family, Genealogical Chart (Box 16)
  - Cain Family, Photographs (Box 16)
  - Hays Family, research notes (Box 16)
  - Harrison Hays, research notes (Box 16)
  - Haskin Family, research notes (Box 16)
  - Peake Family, research notes (Box 16)
  - Rowles Family, research notes (Box 16)
  - Vorhees Family, research notes (Box 16)
  - Washburn Family, research notes (Box 16)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution, correspondence and magazine (Box 16)
  - Sons of the American Revolution, correspondence and application paperwork (Box 16)
  - Census Notes (Box 16)
  - Media Research Bureau (Box 16)
  - Biographical Encyclopedia of the World (Box 16)
  - National Cyclopedia of American Biography (Box 16)
  - Gravestone Photographs (Box 16)
  - Various Papers (Box 16)
  - Viola Root Cameron, correspondence and documents (Box 16)
  - Mrs. Dickinson, correspondence and documents (Box 16)
  - Mrs. H. C. Hays, correspondence and documents (Box 16)
  - L. B. Hays, correspondence and documents (Box 16)
  - Molly Pitcher, correspondence and documents (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with researchers (Box 16)
- Personal and Professional Files (Box 17)
  These materials are organized within folders according to the order in which they were received.
  - Indiana (Box 17)
    - Birth certificate (Box 17)
    - Passports (Box 17)
    - Correspondence (Box 17)
    - Grades at Wabash College (Box 17)
    - Hays and Hays, founding of the firm (Box 17)
    - First Presbyterian Church (Box 17)
    - Flanner House of Indianapolis (Box 17)
    - Indiana Society of Chicago (Box 17)
    - "When Will Hays Sings...", short musical parody written about Will Hays (Box 17)
    - Erroneous Death Report (Box 17)
  - Politics (Box 17)
    - Clippings (Box 17)
    - Correspondence (Box 17)
    - Letters from Governors (Box 17)
    - Teapot Dome Scandal (Box 17)
    - Teapot Dome Scandal clippings (Box 17)
    - Teapot Dome Scandal clippings and correspondence (Box 17)
    - Teapot Dome Scandal statement, (4 folders) (Box 17)
    - Teapot Dome Scandal testimony (Box 17)
    - Washington Notes (Box 17)
    - Washington Notes, 1943 (Box 17)
    - Washington Notes, 1944 (Box 17)
    - Washington Trips (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous materials (Box 17)
  - Military (Box 17)
    - 84th Division Headquarters (Box 17)
    - Adjutant General's Department (Box 17)
    - Atomic Bombs, "The United States Strategic Bombing Survey: the effects of atomic bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki", pamphlet, 30 June 1946 (Box 17)
    - Citizen's Military Training Corp (Box 17)
    - Correspondence (Box 17)
    - Major General Robert C. Davis (Box 17)
    - Defense Day, 1924 (Box 17)
    - General Charles D. Herron (Box 17)
    - Indiana Reserve Officers roster (Box 17)
    - Japan, "Japan's Struggle to end the war" and "Summary Report (Pacific War)", 1 July 1946 (Box 17)
    - Motion Picture Reserve Corp (Box 17)
    - Oath of Office, 1931 (Box 17)
    - Oath of Office, 1936 (Box 17)
    - Paperwork (Box 17)
    - Promotions (Box 17)
    - Reel of film, unidentified (Box 17)
    - State Council of Defense (Box 17)
    - War Activities Committee (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous materials, (2 folders) (Box 17)
  - Motion Pictures (Box 17)
    - AMPP Minutes, 1924-1945 (Box 17)
    - The Banshees, dinner theater program (Box 17)
    - Blackmails (Box 17)
    - Code Development, (2 copies) (Box 17)
    - Contract (Box 17)
    - Compilation of Materials relating to the Movie Period, (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - Compilation of Materials relating to the Movie Period, copy 2, (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - History of Censorship (Box 18)
    - Meeting (Box 18)
    - Memos (Box 18)
    - MPPDA (Box 18)
    - Mussolini Letter, includes autographed letter granting an audience (Box 18)
    - Paris Scrapbook, 1930 (Box 18)
    - Report on Motion Picture (Box 18)
    - Resolution of Appreciation (Box 18)
    - Roach-Mussolini (Box 18)
    - Sound (Box 18)
    - Sound Scrapbook (Box 18)
    - Warner Brothers (Box 18)
    - Warner Brothers Budget, 1938 (Box 18)
    - Warner Brothers, Financial Statistics (Box 18)
    - Warner Brothers resignation (Box 18)
    - Warner-Kent Matter (Box 18)
  - Individuals (Box 18)
    - Davies, Marion (Box 18)
    - Harris, Norval K. (Box 18)
    - Hart, Bill (Box 18)
    - Hays, William H., Jr. (Box 18)
    - Hays, Hinkle C. (Box 18)
    - Herron, Charles D. (Box 18)
    - Howard, Roy, (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Johnson, Osa (Box 18)
    - Johnston, Eric (Box 18)
    - Kron, E. H. (Box 18)
    - McIntyre, O. O. (Box 18)
    - McKenzie, Maurice (Box 18)
    - Moskowitz, Joseph H. (Box 18)
    - Norr, Roy (Box 18)
    - Pearson, Drew (Box 18)
    - Peterson, Frank (Box 18)
    - Quigley, Martin (Box 18)
    - Roach, Hal E. (Box 18)
    - Roddan, Edward L. (Box 18)
    - Seabury-Rubin Correspondence (Box 18)
    - Schenck, Charles (Box 18)
    - Schenck, Charles, testimony (Box 18)
    - Selznick, David O. (Box 18)
    - Stettinius, Edward (Box 18)
    - Walker, Frank (Box 18)
    - Warner, Harry M. (Box 18)
    - Warner, Harry M., regarding anticytotoxic serum (Box 18)
    - Young, Owen (Box 18)
    - Z (Box 18)
    - Zanuck, Darryl, (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Zanuck, Darryl, senate investigation (Box 18)
- Correspondence (Box 19)
  - Condolence letters, 1 Mar-15 Mar 1954 (Box 19)
  - Condolence letters, 16 Mar-23 Sept 1954 (Box 19)
  - Condolence letters, undated; (2 folders) (Box 19)
  - Condolence telegrams (Box 19)
  - Condolence notes (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 21)
  - Boettinger, John (Box 21)
    Includes three bound volumes of correspondence.
  - Coolidge, Calvin (Box 21)
  - Edison, Thomas (Box 21)
  - Harding, Warren G. (Box 21)
  - Hoover, Herbert (Box 21)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot (Box 21)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Box 21)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin (Box 21)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 21)
  - Taft, William (Box 21)
  - Wright, Orville. Autographed photograph of the first manned flight, Kitty Hawk, NC, 17 Dec 1903 (Box 21)
  - Letter written by a very young Will H. Hays, Jr., bound in leather, Jan. 18, 1887 (Box 26)
- Articles (Box 21)
  - Articles about Will Hays, (5 folders)
  - Politics, including Harding inauguration
  - Movie clippings
  - Motion Pictures
  - World War II
  - Invasion, 6 June 1944
  - Divorce, (3 folders)
  - Death notices, (5 folders)
  - Death notices, Crawfordsville, IN
  - Death notices, Indianapolis, IN
  - Death notices, Los Angeles, CA
  - Death notices, New York, NY
  - Death notices, Sullivan, IN
  - Death notices, Terre Haute, IN
  - Death notices, Wabash College
  - Articles about William Harrison Hays (Box 23)
  - Aviation (Box 23)
  - Censorship (Box 23)
  - Radio (Box 23)
  - Republican Party (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 23)
- Audio-Visual Materials (Box 20)
  Consist mostly of LP audio recordings.
  - Tribute to Franklin Delano Roosevelt, bound, with sleeves, 15 April 1945 (Box 20)
  - "House warming", 22 April 1933 (Box 24)
  - "Mr. Hays", 31 Oct 1935 (Box 24)
  - "Award to Walt Disney", 22 Jan 1937 (Box 24)
  - "Mr. Will Hays speaking at 25th anniversary dinner to Adolph Zukor", Hotel Waldorf Astoria, NY, 29 Mar 1937 (Box 24)
  - "Premiere of 'Captains Courageous'", 11 May 1937 (Box 24)
  - "American Red Cross Convention", 13 May 1937 (Box 24)
  - "Story of Industry", 28 Dec 1937 (Box 24)
  - "Will Hays, WABC", 12 Sept 1938 (Box 24)
  - "Herald Tribune Forum, WJZ", 25 Oct 1938; (2 records) (Box 24)
  - "Presbyterian Church, WOB", 30 Oct 1938 (Box 24)
  - "Three Mirrors of America, WJZ", 12 July 1939; (3 records) (Box 24)
  - "Indiana Society Banquet, recording of theme song 'Hays-a-poppin''", 13 Dec 1941 (Box 24)
  - To the Red Cross, Irene Siems, undated (Box 24)
  - William Harrison Hays speeches, (3 recordings) (Box 24)
- Miscellaneous (Box 21)
  - "Will H. Hays: Republican Politician," by Richard J. Cinclair, dissertation, pp. 1-100, 1969 (Box 21)
  - "Will H. Hays: Republican Politician," by Richard J. Cinclair, dissertation, pp. 101-194, 1969 (Box 21)
  - Release agreement for unnamed Will H. Hays, Jr. book, signed by Helen V. Fischer, Feb. 25, 1985 (Box 26)
  - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 26)